here's an interesting fact about the 3 4
five right triangle find the in Center
as the intersection of the three angle
bis sectors draw the in radius to each
of the sides and draw the in circle do
you know the area of the in circle of
the 345 right triangle one way to figure
this out is to compute the area of the
triangle two ways first of all the area
is 1 12 * 3 * 4 but the area of the
triangle can also be found as the sum of
the areas of these three subt triangles
each with a height of R and with bases
of length three four and five so the
area is also 1 12 3 * r + 1 12 4 * r +
12 5 * R from these two computations
then we see that 6 = 6 * R but that
means the in radius R is of length 1 so
that the in circle has a radius of one
giving it an area of Pi it's amazing
that we get PI from the 345 right
triangle